topfreeintro.com 2019-12-13

# Privacy Policy | topfreeintro.com

### Privacy Policy of [ **www.topfreeintro.com**](http://www.topfreeintro.com/)

Our site collects some Personal Data from its Users.

#### Data Controller and Owner

#### Types of Data collected

Among the types of Personal Data that our site collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookie, Usage Data, Email, First Name and Last Name.

Other Personal Data collected may be described in other sections of this privacy policy or by dedicated explanation text contextually with the Data collection.  
The Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or collected automatically when using our site.  
Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools – by our site or by the owners of third party services used by our site, unless stated otherwise, serves to identify Users and remember their preferences, for the sole purpose of providing the service required by the User.  
Failure to provide certain Personal Data may make it impossible for our site to provide its services.

The User assumes responsibility for the Personal Data of third parties published or shared through our site and declares to have the right to communicate or broadcast them, thus relieving the Data Controller of all responsibility.

#### **Mode and place of processing the Data**

##### **Methods of processing**

The Data Controller processes the Data of Users in a proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.  
The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Data Controller, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of the site (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Data Controller at any time.

##### **Place**

The Data is processed at the Data Controller’s operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved with the processing are located. For further information, please contact the Data Controller.

##### **Retention time**

The Data is kept for the time necessary to provide the service requested by the User, or stated by the purposes outlined in this document, and the User can always request that the Data Controller suspend or remove the data.

#### **The use of the collected Data**

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow our site to provide its services, as well as for the following purposes: Analytics, Contacting the User, Managing email addresses, sending messages, Displaying content from external platforms, Content commenting, SPAM protection, Traffic optimization and distribution, Interaction with external social networks and platforms.

The Personal Data used for each purpose is outlined in the specific sections of this document.

#### **Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data**

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

  * #### **Analytics**

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

##### **Google Analytics (Google)**

** ** Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of our site, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.

Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)

#####  Wordpress Stats (Automattic Inc.)

WordPress Stats is an analytics service provided by Automattic Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://automattic.com/privacy/)

  * #### **Advertisements**

We also use third party advertisements on topfreeintro.com to support our site. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site.

##### **Google Adsense (Google)**

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on www.topfreeintro.com.

Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to www.topfreeintro.com and other sites on the Internet.

Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – <http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/>

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include ….Google Adsense

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on www.topfreeintro.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

www.topfreeintro.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. www.topfreeintro.com’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

  * #### **Contacting the User**

##### **Mailing List or Newsletter**

By registering to the mailing list or to the newsletter, the User’s email address will be added to the contact list of those who may receive email messages containing information of commercial or promotional nature concerning our site. Your email address might also be added to this list as a result of signing up to our site or after performing a purchase.

Personal Data collected: Email, First Name and Last Name.

##### **Contact form**

By filling in the contact form with their Data, the Users authorizes our site to use these details to reply to requests for information, quotes or any other kind of request as indicated by the form’s header.

Personal Data collected: Email, First Name and Last Name.

  * #### **Managing email addresses and sending messages**

These services make it possible to manage a database of email contacts to communicate with the User via email.  
The services are used to collect data concerning the date and time when the mail is viewed by the User, as well as when the User interacts with incoming mail, such as by clicking on links included in the email.

##### **Mailchimp (Mailchimp)**

Mailchimp is an email address management and message sending service provided by Mailchimp Inc.

Personal Data collected: Email, First Name.

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/)

  * #### **Content commenting**

Content commenting services allow Users to make and publish their comments on the contents of our site.  
Depending on the settings chosen by the Owner, Users may also leave anonymous comments. If there is an email address among the Personal Data provided by the User, it may be used to send notifications of comments on the same content. Users are responsible for the content of their own comments.  
If a content commenting service provided by third parties is installed, it may still collect web traffic data for the pages where the comment service is installed, even when users do not use the content commenting service.

##### Comment system managed directly

our site has its own internal content comment system.

Personal Data collected: Email, First Name and Last Name.

##### **Facebook Comments (Facebook)**

Facebook Comments is a content commenting service provided by Facebook Inc. enabling the User to leave comments and share them on the Facebook platform.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation.php)

  * #### **Interaction with external social networks and platforms**

These services allow interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of our site.  
The interaction and information obtained by our site are always subject to the User’s privacy settings for each social network.  
If a service enabling interaction with social networks is installed it may still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

##### **Shareaholic (Shareaholic, Inc.)**

Shareaholic is a service provided by Shareaholic, Inc., which displays a widget that allows interaction with social networks and external platforms as well as sharing the contents of our site.  
Depending on the configuration, this service can display widgets belonging to third parties such as the managers of social networks where interactions are shared. In this case, also the third parties that provide the widget will be informed of interactions and Usage Data on the pages where this service is installed.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](https://shareaholic.com/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://shareaholic.com/privacy/choices)

  * #### **SPAM protection**

These services analyze the traffic of our site, potentially containing Users’ Personal Data, with the purpose of filtering it from parts of traffic, messages and content that are recognized as SPAM.

##### **Akismet (Automattic Inc.)**

Akismet is a SPAM protection service provided by Automattic Inc.

Personal Data collected: Various types of Data.

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://automattic.com/privacy/)

  * #### **Traffic optimization and distribution**

These services allow our site to distribute their content using servers located across different countries and to optimize their performance.  
Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and the way these services are implemented. Their function is to filter communications between our site and the User’s browser.  
Considering the widespread distribution of this system, it is difficult to determine the locations to which the contents that may contain Personal Information User are transferred.

##### **CloudFlare (Cloudflare)**

CloudFlare is a traffic optimization and distribution service provided by CloudFlare Inc.  
The way CloudFlare is integrated means that it filters all the traffic through our site, i.e., communication between our site and the User’s browser, while also allowing analytical data from our site to be collected.

Personal Data collected: Various types of Data.

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.cloudflare.com/security-policy)

  * #### Displaying content from external platforms

These services allow you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of our site and interact with them.  
If a service of this kind is installed, it may still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when users do not use it.

##### Youtube video widget (Google)

Youtube is a video content visualization service provided by Google Inc. that allows our site to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data.

Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.it/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

#### **Additional information about Data collection and processing**

##### **Legal action**

The User’s Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Data Controller, in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of our site or the related services.  
The User is aware of the fact that the Data Controller may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities.

##### **Additional information about User’s Personal Data**

In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, our site may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request.

##### **System Logs and Maintenance**

For operation and maintenance purposes, our site and any third party services may collect files that record interaction with our site (System Logs) or use for this purpose other Personal Data (such as IP Address).

##### **Information not contained in this policy**

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Data Controller at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document.

##### **The rights of Users**

Users have the right, at any time, to know whether their Personal Data has been stored and can consult the Data Controller to learn about their contents and origin, to verify their accuracy or to ask for them to be supplemented, cancelled, updated or corrected, or for their transformation into anonymous format or to block any data held in violation of the law, as well as to oppose their treatment for any and all legitimate reasons. Requests should be sent to the Data Controller at the contact information set out above.

Our site does not support “Do Not Track” requests.  
To determine whether any of the third party services it uses honor the “Do Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies.

##### **Changes to this privacy policy**

The Data Controller reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom. If a User objects to any of the changes to the Policy, the User must cease using our site and can request that the Data Controller erase the Personal Data. Unless stated otherwise, the then-current privacy policy applies to all Personal Data the Data Controller has about Users.

##### **Information about this privacy policy**

The Data Controller is responsible for this privacy policy, prepared starting from the modules provided by Iubenda and hosted on Iubenda’s servers.

#### **Contacting Us**

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below.

topfreeintro.com

shaheen@topfreeintro.com

Latest update: November 15, 2014
